

Ahmed Imtiaz

(+92) 03330465698

Date of birth: 11/08/1995

Email address: writetoahmedimtiaz@gmail.com

Website: https://imahmedimtiaz.github.io

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-imtiaz-3578911ab

• Address: Gulshan-e-Ravi, Lahore (Pakistan)

ABOUT ME

A confident and reliable IT professional with 3+ years of experience of working as a Technical support engineer a nd resolving any support issues that are raised to the service desk. Possessing professional training & certifications from CISCO, Microsoft, VMware etc. and have proven track record in network/system support helping clients and colleagues resolve complex technical IT issues. An excellent communicator can relate well with people at all levels and has the flexibility of working well as part of a team and on my own.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network & System Engineer

FutureNow Technologies [01/2022 - Current]

City: Lahore

Country: Pakistan

- Proactively ensure the highest levels of systems and infrastructure availability
- Continuous network traffic, critical nodes/endpoints monitoring & ensuring the availability of internet
- Configuration & maintenance of CISCO IP phones & IP Cameras
- Providing technical support to all users across the business
- Identifying, diagnosing and rectifying any issues in computer hardware, software, services and applications
- Service desk ticket management (Assign, follow up, resolution & close)
- Setting up new user's AD & Email accounts & deal with password/login issues
- Scanning of computer systems & servers using BitDefender to ensure virus free IT environment
- Creating & configuring virtual machines in ESXi & connecting them with network.
- Support in day-to-day datacenter operations
- Liaise with vendors and other IT personnel for problem resolution
- Providing step-by-step technical help, both verbal & written, including procedural documents

Systems Support Engineer

Dunya News [04/2021 - 12/2021]

City: Lahore
Country: Pakistan

- Continuous monitoring and maintenance of computer systems and networks.
- Providing technical support to all users across the business.
- Responding and resolving the support requests and service tickets in a timely manner
- Identifying, diagnosing and rectifying any issues in computer hardware, software, services and applications
- · Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners
- Setting up AD accounts for new users and assist users with password or login problems

IT Support Engineer

Lahore Logistics [03/2019 - 02/2021]

City: Lahore
Country: Pakistan

- Responsible for software installation and troubleshooting on workstations
- Follow up and communicate with users on their IT support incidents and service requests with resolution and escalation
- · Diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults and replace parts as required
- Providing technical support either face-to-face or remotely, to help set up systems or resolve issues

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BS Software Engineering

Lahore Leads University, Pakistan [2014 - 2018]

F.Sc Pre-Engineering

Govt. college of science, Pakistan [2012 - 2014]

High School

Pak Angles High School, Pakistan [2010 - 2012]

DIGITAL SKILLS

IT Support & Troubleshooting / System Support / Network Support / Computer Hardware & Software / Software installation & patch management / Microsoft windows 7/8/10, Android, IOS / Microsoft office/ Office 365

Network and System Administration

Strong knowledge of Cisco IOS / ACL , Traffic Filtering / VPNs(GRE, DMVPN, Site-to-Site, Point-to-Site) / IP Addressing & Subnetting / LAN, RIP, RIPv2, EIGRP, OSPF, VLAN, VTP, STP, Inter-VLAN Routing / Setting Telnet, SSH and Remote Control Connection / Windows Server (Active Directory, DCHP, DNS, IIS) / Virtualization: VMware ESXI, vSphere client, vCenter

TRAININGS & CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate 200-301

CISCO

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft

Microsoft Certified: Azure administrator associate

Microsoft

MCSA Training

Online/Udemy

VMware Datacenter Virtualization Training

Online/Udemy